得在这次阻止他们
They've got to stop them in this series.
-靠  -不是吧
- Geez! Damn it! - Come on!
在德克萨斯  神圣的三位一体是上帝
In Texas, the Holy Trinity is God,
橄榄球与烧烤
football and barbeque,
顺序可以互换
not necessarily in that order.
谁输谁赢无所谓  让分后算我赢就行
I don't care if you win, just cover the damn spread.
妈  你又开始赌球了吗
Mom, are you betting again?
没有
No.
球迷们如坐针毡
...fans on their feet,
希望队伍展开防守
trying to urge the defense on.
橄榄球中  攻方有4次进攻机会  弃踢是常见战术
第四攻了
Fourth down.
必须得弃踢
Gotta punt.
必须
Gotta.
数据上来说  总在第四攻弃踢
Statistically, always punting on fourth down
弃踢是将球踢远  虽然球权也转移给对手
但对方就必须从较远的地方开始进攻
是十分不合理的
makes no sense.
数据上来说  你就是个傻逼
Statistically, you're a dumbass.
当德州农工大学队
When the Aggies give up the ball
被对方在自家五码线进攻时
on their own five-yard line,
对方队伍有92%的几率会得分
the opposing team has a 92% chance of scoring.
当他们从自家场地深处弃踢出去
When they punt from deep in their own territory,
对方队伍还是有77%的几率得分
the other team still has a 77% chance of scoring.
但他们继续进攻有50%几率再得4次进攻机会
But since they convert on fourth down 50% of the time,
所以计算显示他们不该弃踢
the math says they should never punt again.
好了  你偷偷跟妈说
Okay, you can tell me,
他亲生父亲到底是谁
who's his real daddy?
谢尔顿  我踢球与当教练一辈子了
Sheldon, I've been playing and coaching football all my life.
我觉得你算得不对
I don't think your math is right.
是吗
Really?
你等等
Hang on.
不  没算错
No, it's right.
让农工队只是射门得分的话
...able to hold A&M to a field goal,
他们就只会落后6分
they'll only be down six points.
是你的牙医吗
Is it your dentist?
那个戴眼镜的小个子
The little guy with the glasses?
放心跟我说实话
You can tell me.
♪ 世上没人比我强壮 ♪
♪ Nobody else is stronger than I am ♪
♪ 昨天我移了一座山 ♪
♪ Yesterday I moved a mountain ♪
♪ 我相信我能当你的英雄 ♪
♪ I bet I could be your hero ♪
♪ 我是个了不起的小家伙 ♪
♪ I am a mighty little man ♪
少
年
谢尔顿
跟你说  我有点担心我妈
I got to tell you, I'm a little worried about my mother.
她整天赌这些球赛
She keeps betting on these football games,
之后哪天可能就会来个意大利小伙
next thing you know, there's an Italian fella
来把她的小货车开走抵债
driving off with her pickup truck.
你觉得谢尔顿说得对吗
You think Sheldon's right?
哪件事情
About what?
弃踢还有他的计算
The punting and the math.
我相信应该对
I should think so.
从他六岁时起  我们家纳税就是他在弄
He's been doing our taxes since he's six years old.
我们也没被税局稽查
We never been audited.
这倒是
That's true.
他去年还帮我们拿到退税呢
He even got us that nice refund last year.
为什么今天不是妈载我去学校
How come Mom's not taking me to school?
因为有时候
'Cause once in a while,
你老爸也会想跟你相处一下啊
your dad wants to spend some time with you.
我的小谢仔
My little Shel-man.
但是妈的车有后座
But Mom's car has a backseat.
数据上来说  我坐那里比较安全
Statistically, I'm much safer there.
我刚好也想跟你聊一下这个数据
Hey, I'm glad you brought up statistically.
你觉得你昨天说的德州农工大学队的数据
You think those numbers you talked about for Texas A&M
也能用在我带的队伍上吗
would apply to my JV squad?
没道理不能啊
I don't see why not.
数学与前任校长不同的是  数学不歧视人
Unlike our former principal, math doesn't discriminate.
你不会是想用他的建议吧
You're not thinking about taking his advice, are you?
-用不着你管  -可是他是错的
- Never you mind. - But he's wrong.
大家都知道第四攻应该弃踢
Everybody knows you punt on fourth down.
为什么大家都知道就等于它是对的
Why does everybody knowing something make it right?
因为
Because.
美国就是因此而伟大
That's what makes this country great.
许多年后
Many years later,
我哥也用了这句话
my brother would use this same argument
跟法官解释
in front of a judge.
但他在电话亭里撒尿的事还是被定罪了
He was still convicted for urinating in a phone booth.
靠
Oh, damn it.
我去让弃踢手上场
I'll send in the punting team.
等等  你等等
Hang on. Hang on.
怎么
What?
继续进攻
Let's go for it.
为什么  我们时间还很充足啊
Why? We got plenty of time.
我知道  还是想要继续进攻
I know. Still want to go for it.
我们在12码线上呢  大家都知道该保守弃踢
We're on the 12-yard line. Everybody know you punt.
谁说大家都知道就等于它是对的
Why does everybody knowing something make it right?
但是在我们球门口啊  教练
But we're on the 12-yard line, Coach.
教练让我们继续进攻
Okay, Coach says we're going for it.
白痴弟弟
Stupid brother.
-什么  -没事
- What? - Nothing.
左侧突破  准备  散开
Power left jumbo on two, on two. Ready, break!
狼队在第四攻选择继续进攻
And your Wolves are going for it on fourth down.
什么鬼  弃踢啊
What the hell? Punt!
数据上来说  继续进攻比较好
Statistically, they're better off going for it.
-谁说的  -我儿子
- Says who? - My little boy.
这就是为什么大家都弃踢
That's why everybody punts.
这简直就是脑袋抽风
That was just plain foolishness.
你小儿子可真天才啊
Your little boy's a real genius.
他还真是天才
Well, actually he is.
不是吧
Come on.
犯规  防守方场上人数过多
Too many men on the field, defense.
第四攻重来
Replay fourth down.
感谢老天
Ah. Thank you, Jesus.
我现在可以叫弃踢手上场了吗
Now, can I send in the punt team?
教练
Coach?
他们再度继续进攻
And they're going for it again.
什么鬼啊  弃踢啊
What the hell? Punt!
提醒我下次跟你说我拿到国税局退税的事
Remind me to tell you about the tax refund I got from the IRS.
开始
Set. Hut!
上上上上上
Go, go, go, go, go, go!
上啊
Go! Whoo!
冲啊  冲啊
Go, go, go! Go!
来到了30码线  20码  10码
He's at the 30, the 20, the 10.
达阵得分  狼队
Touchdown, Wolves!
我就没怀疑过你  教练  没怀疑过
I never had any doubt, Coach. Never had any doubt.
看到没  太好啦
Oh, booyah! Yes.
晚安啦  宝贝
Sweet dreams, baby.
晚安姥姥
Night, Meemaw.
我能请你帮个忙吗
Can I ask you a favor?
-可以啊  什么事  -你还记得
- Sure. What? - You know those statistics
你跟你爸爸说的那些什么数据吗
that you were talking about with your dad?
那些数据也能套用到...
Could... could that be applied to, say,
比如说下周的牛仔与包装工队比赛吗
who might win the Cowboys-Packers game next week?
能不能更详细到差多少分之类的
And, more specifically, by how much?
如果我有足够数据  应该可以给出合理猜测
I suppose with enough data I could make a reasonable guess.
我不要猜测  我要确切的
I don't want a guess, I want to know.
妈说不可以赌博
Mom said you're not supposed to gamble.
睡你的觉  死小孩
Sleep, child!
-妈  -在这里呢
- Mom? - In here!
我明天把那些数据弄给你
I'll get those numbers to you tomorrow.
来哄他睡觉
Just tucking him in.
我有东西给你
I got something for you.
是脏的
It's dirty.
因为这是比赛用过的球
Well, that's 'cause it's the game ball.
这是你应得的  因为你帮我们赢了比赛
And you earned it, 'cause you helped us win.
好吧  但你能先洗一洗吗
Okay, but can you wash it?
谢尔顿  你爸爸是在夸你  以你为荣呢
Sheldon, your daddy's telling you he's proud of you.
好吧  谢谢你  爸爸
I see. Thank you, Dad.
不客气
You're welcome.
但我还是不要碰它
I'm still never touching that.
去帮他擦干净吧
Let's go wipe it off.
接下来的五周
For the next five weeks,
我继续帮我爸爸套用数据
I continued to help my father apply statistics
来执教他的队伍
to coach his team.
毫无意外地  队伍一直在赢
Not surprisingly, they continued to win,
这让我在学校的地位冲上云霄
which changed my status in the school dramatically.
-他来啦  -谢尔顿
- There he is! - Yo, Sheldon!
谢狗
Shel-dog!
数学哥
Math man!
小可爱
Hey, cutie.
简直就是一场恶梦
It was a nightmare.
谢狗
Shel-dog!
拥抱  弄乱头发  击掌
Hugging, hair tousling, high fives.
我的人气冲上云霄  我在空中的时间也长了
And as my popularity grew, so did my time aloft.
我到处在找你呢
Hey, I've been looking all over for you.
你知道我们现在人气有多高吗
Do you know how popular we are?
-我们吗  -对啊
- We? - Yeah.
我放出消息  说我有帮忙你算橄榄球的数据
I put the word out I was helping you with the football stats.
他们看我是亚洲人就信了
And since I'm Asian, they bought it.
你享受这感觉我替你高兴
Well, I'm glad you're enjoying it.
你不享受吗
You're not?
今天一下午  我被人摸了82次
I was touched 82 times this afternoon.
你说"摸"是什么意思
What do you mean, "touched"?
不是不合适地乱"摸"
Not inappropriately.
是开心地
Joyfully.
充满热情地
Affectionately.
还有一个拉拉队员抱我入她胸
A cheerleader hugged me to her bosom.
太爽了吧
That's amazing.
我不要再击掌了
No more high fives.
我不想一直洗手
I can't keep washing my hands.
这不是我的小助理教练吗
There's my little assistant coach.
你好啊  老爸
Hello, Dad.
关于下星期的比赛
You have any more, uh, arithmetic ideas
还有什么算出来的小妙招吗
for next week's game?
有啊  但我想先写完作业
I do, but I'm trying to finish my homework.
看起来很复杂啊
Looks complicated.
这是高等化学  不复杂啊
Advanced chemistry. It's not.
你们在干嘛呢
What are you guys doing?
你弟弟跟我在讨论讨论下周
Your brother and I are gonna knock around a few ideas
对弗里波特队的比赛打法
for the Freeport game.
我能帮忙吗
Can I help?
可以啊  帮忙跑去我车上
Actually, yeah. Run out to my truck.
前座有一个口袋计算器
There's a little, uh, pocket calculator on my front seat.
我有个礼物给你
I got you a present.
我想这个能帮忙你算
Thought it might help with your figuring.
我不需要计算器啊  爸  我就是计算器
I don't need a calculator, Dad. I am one.
行吧
Sure.
还是去拿吧
Go get it anyway.
是太阳能的
It's solar-powered.
你能想象到吗
Can you imagine that?
小乔治  小声点
Georgie, turn that down!
什么
What?
看看你房间  快给我整理干净
And look at this room. You need to clean this mess up.
我等会再弄
I'll get to it later.
不行  你现在就整理
No, you'll get to it now.
我不想
I don't feel like it.
不管你想不想都现在去打扫
Well, your feelings have nothing to do with it.
也不要再丢那个球了
And stop throwing that ball.
我房间让你这么看了烦  那你来打扫
My room bothers you so much, you clean it.
够了  你被禁足了  听到没
That's it! You are grounded! You hear me?!
怎么回事
The hell?
我的小饼饼
There's my little Moonpie.
你抽空帮我看这周的比赛了吗
Did you get a chance to look at this week's games for me?
-还没  -你知道没剩多少时间了吧
- Not yet. - You understand there's a little time crunch involved.
姥姥有一些欠款得还上呢
Meemaw's got some outstanding loans I need to pay back.
抱歉  但我得先写完作业
I'm sorry, I have to finish my homework
然后去帮完我爸爸之后才有空
and then I have to help my dad.
来嘛
Come on.
我是你亲爱的姥姥
I'm your meemaw.
我还给你做饼干
I make you cookies.
咱们俩互利互惠一下如何
How 'bout a little quid pro quo?
虽然我挺喜欢你用成语  但不了
As much as I enjoy your use of Latin, no.
谢利  该准备上床睡觉了
Shelly, time to get ready for bed.
我还没写完呢
But I'm not done.
小家伙  别跟我顶嘴
Don't you sass me, too, young man.
去刷牙睡觉
Brush your teeth and get to bed.
我觉得你的怒火有点发泄错地方了
I think your anger might be a little misdirected.
你也别来跟我挑事
Don't you start with me either.
瞧  你还是在拿旁人出气
Now, see, you're still shootin' wide.
晚上好  库珀太太
Good evening, Mrs. Cooper.
我能和谢尔顿聊聊吗
Can I speak to Sheldon?
不行  你不能
No, you can't speak to Sheldon.
很晚了  他已经上床睡了
It's late. He's in bed.
我想问他要不要跟我一起去派对
Oh. I was hoping he might like to go to a party with me.
大家都集体发疯了吗
Has everyone lost their mind?
他还是个孩子  丹
He's a little boy, Tam!
晚安
Good night!
天啊  今晚你那张嘴好像机关枪似地
Good Lord, that mouth of yours is a machine gun tonight.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
试着算出下周日海豚队
Trying to calculate the odds of the Dolphins
让分后赢的几率
covering the spread next Sunday.
我喜欢海豚
I like dolphins.
他们用脑袋上的洞来说话
They talk out of that hole in their head.
你好
Hello.
丹
Tam?
你怎么会在这儿
What are you doing here?
你愿意和我一起去派对吗
Would you like to go to a party with me?
我不想和任何人一起去派对
I don't want to go to a party with anyone.
我愿意
I would!
拜托了  谢尔顿
Please, Sheldon.
就在马路对面
It's right across the street.
带我进去  然后你就可以回来睡觉了
Just get me in, and you can go back to bed.
我得先问下我妈妈
I have to ask my mom.
不用了  她知道派对的事
No need. She knows all about the party.
那好吧
All right, then.
给我一分钟换身衣服
I need a minute to change.
-你为什么穿这个  -能让我看起来成熟些
- Why are you wearing that? - It makes me look older.
先把话说清楚  一把你弄进去
Just so we're clear, once you get in,
我就回家了
I'm going home.
好呀  谢尔顿
Hey! Sheldon!
你这是干什么
What are you doing?
各位快看啊  谢尔顿来了
Hey, everybody, check it out! Sheldon's here!
希望孩子们不会被那派对吵醒
I hope that doesn't wake up the kids.
要不要我去那边说说他们
Should I go over there and say something?
我觉得有这必要
I think you should.
我刚只是装有心
I was bluffin'.
别逼我把袜子穿回去
Don't make me put my socks back on.
算了
Never mind.
晚安
Good night.
我朝小乔治大吼了  我觉得很内疚
I feel bad about yelling at Georgie.
是他该骂
He deserved it.
你应该多吼他几次
You should do it more.
我想他是觉得被冷落了
I think he's feeling left out
因为你和谢尔顿现在常黏在一起
now that you and Sheldon are spending so much time together.
你在逗我吗
Are you kiddin' me?
是你一直叫我找到和谢尔顿的共同话题
You're always saying to find something in common with Sheldon.
现在我找到了  你又说我冷落小乔治了
And now that I have, you're telling me I'm ignoring Georgie?
我没那么说
I'm not saying that.
我只是提醒你
I'm just reminding you
你有两个儿子
that you got two sons.
我知道
I know.
我还有个也应该多跟她相处的女儿
I also got a daughter I need to spend more time with.
确实是的
You do.
但我不担心她
But I wouldn't worry about her.
她就是个小天使
She's an angel.
谢尔顿  谢尔顿  谢尔顿
Sheldon! Sheldon! Sheldon!
-放我下来  -谢尔顿  谢尔顿
- Put me down! - Sheldon! Sheldon!
快把我放下来
I said put me down.
放我下来  我不喜欢这样
Put me down! I'm not enjoying this!
米希  你在这儿干吗
Missy, what are you doing here?!
放纵享乐  你又在这儿干吗
Cuttin' loose. What are you doing here?
慢点  慢点
Slowly! Slowly!
慢点
Slowly!
你也来了
You, too?!
你好  小乔治
Hello, Georgie!
你不应该来这里
You're not supposed to be here.
你也不该来  你被禁足了
Neither are you! You're grounded!
走吧
Come on.
你们俩现在就给我回家
Both of you are going home. Now.
-谢天谢地  -不要嘛
- Oh, thank goodness. - Aw.
青春期对你影响如何
How's puberty treating you?
它可让我长大了许多
Because it is knocking me for a loop.
对吧
Right?
我父母居然没发现我去纵情派对了
Somehow, my parents didn't find out about me partying heartily.
但蜡烛两头烧
But I did pay a price
确实让我付出了代价
for burning the candle at both ends.
B+  写出你的计算过程
我数学考试时犯了错
I made a mistake on a math test.
我太累了  我在脑子里做了运算
In my exhaustion, I did all the calculations in my head,
结果像动物园里的动物一样  忘了写出计算过程
and, like a common zoo animal, forgot to show my work.
我刚遇到派对上的一个女生
I just saw one of those girls from the party,
她对我做了这个动作  像承认了我的存在
and she acknowledged my existence by doing this.
人生首次感到如此有存在感
I've never felt so alive.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
不好
No, I'm not.
这又怎么样
Yeah, so?
B+  这是走向终点的开始
A B-plus-- that's the beginning of the end.
什么终点
The end of what?
我的人生
My life.
如果我不做出改变  谁知道我会堕落到什么地步
If I don't make some changes, who knows how far I'll fall.
说不定我会变成瘾君子  或律师
I could wind up a drug addict, or a lawyer.
你会不会反应过激了
Is it possible you're overreacting?
不  从今天起  我不再帮橄榄球队了
No. Starting today, I'm done helping the football team.
你这样妹子们再也不会这么跟我打招呼了
But if you do that, girls will no longer greet me like this.
我会这么跟你打招呼
I'll greet you like that.
这不一样啦
It's not the same.
让我自己从这些事中抽身
Extricating myself from this situation
并非易事
was not going to be easy.
我父亲指望着我  我姥姥指望着我
My father was counting on me, Meemaw was counting on me,
学校也指望着我
the school was counting on me.
深思熟虑后  我决定
After much thought, I decided to employ
采取最靠得住的战略策略
the one strategic maneuver I knew I could count on.
打小报告
I tattled.
妈妈
Mom?
谢尔顿得了B+  真是太糟糕了
Sheldon got a B-plus! That's terrible for him!
我对你们三个非常失望
I'm very disappointed in all three of you.
没错  米希  这是给你上芭蕾课穿的
That is right. Missy, this is for your ballet class.
你们不许去派对玩
We do not go to parties.
我非常失望
I am very disappointed.
我要去给队伍弄些装备  你想一起去吗
Got to go pick up some equipment for the team; you want to join me?
去不了  我被禁足了
Can't. I'm grounded.
是啊  不过
Yeah, well...
你不说  我也不会说出去
I won't tell if you won't.
谢尔顿去吗
Sheldon going?
那个背信弃义的小崽子  当然不去
That little snitch? Absolutely not.
谢尔顿还会帮你算数吗
Sheldon still gonna help you with the math?
我想不会了
I don't think so.
但我听说他那个亚洲人朋友也会算
But I did hear his little Asian friend can do it.
你好
Hello.
话说
So...
这个周日油工队赔率是让四分
Oilers are a four-point favorite for this Sunday's game,
但是是油工队主场  所以我想赌主队让分赢盘
but it's a home game, so I'm thinking I give the points.
你觉得呢
What do you think?
我觉得我又得告发你了
I think I have to tell on you again.
有本事就去啊  你妈能怎样  禁我的足吗
Go ahead. What's your mama gonna do, ground me?
买油工队  让分赢盘
Take the Oilers, give the points.
我爱你  小饼饼
I love you, Moonpie.
告诉你们  油工队输了那场比赛
For the record, the Oilers lost that game
对手四次触地得分
by four touchdowns.
姥姥再也没问过我意见了
Meemaw never asked for my advice again.
来啊  来啊  我靠
Come on, come on, come on. Damn it!
好了
Okay.
再一次
One more time.
妈妈需要台新的摩托艇
Mama needs a new Jet Ski!
结果是
And...
王八羔子
rat bastard!
你好吗  康妮
How you doin' there, Connie?
你好啊  文森特
Hey, Vincent.
你怎么到路易斯安那州来了
What brings you to Louisiana?
等等  别告诉我
Wait, don't tell me.
你是来看托尼·奥兰多[演员]的
You're here to see Tony Orlando.
不是的
'Fraid not.
反正你该去看看他的表演
Oh, well, you ought to check him out.
他会让你大吃一惊的[脱掉袜子]
He'll, uh, knock your socks off.
我喜欢穿着袜子
I like my socks on.
康妮  你让我很为难
Connie, you're putting me in a very awkward position.
我玩基诺彩票赢了一台面包烤箱
I won a toaster oven playing keno.
你想要吗
You want it?
我自己有
I got one.
我想要我的钱
I want my money.
好啊
All right.
稍等
Hang on.
你的外套很好看
That's a very nice jacket.
你穿着看上去很帅
You're looking dapper.
这个赌场送我免费住宿
Hey, they comp my room here.
你也有这个待遇吗
They do that for you?
事实上  他们不太欢迎我来
Actually, they frown upon my presence here.
我还拿到了自助早餐的优惠券
Oh. I also get a coupon for the breakfast buffet.
你应该去问问
You should look into that.
康斯坦丝
Constance!
耐心点  文森索
Patience, Vincenzo.
赞啦
Yes!
太好了  这才像话嘛
All right, now we're talking.
你愿意收硬币作为头期款吗
Will you take a down payment in quarters?
我有选择吗
Do I have a choice?
开捞吧
Start scoopin'.
我得去看托尼·奥兰多了
I got to go see Tony Orlando.
再给我一个杯子
Hey, I need another cup!